"No Trespassing"
((イタチ : 南賀ノ神社本堂
その右奥から ７枚目の畳の下に➡
In the main hall in Nakano Shrine
beneath the seventh tatami mat
from the inner right side
(一族 秘密の集会場がある))
is the clan's hidden meeting room.
I see... So that's what it is...
(サスケ)そうか… そういうことか。
(フガク)さすが オレの子だ。
That's my boy.
(ミコト)あなたのことばかり
話してるのよ お父さん))
Your father only talks about you.
母さんと どんな話
してたんだろう… 父さん。
I wonder what kind of things
Father was saying to Mother.
If you wish to kill me,
resent me, hate me!
(イタチ)このオレを殺したくば
恨め 憎め))
《兄さん… アンタを殺すためなら➡
Brother... No matter what darkness
may await me,
この先が どんな闇だろうと
オレは突き進んでやる！
if it means killing you,
I will meet it head on!
どんなことがあっても
力を手に入れてやる！》
I will obtain that power
no matter what!
力を… 憎しみを手に入れ
オレは ここに来た。
I obtained power and hatred,
and now I'm here.
イタチ… アンタは ここで死ぬ！
Itachi! This is where you'll die!
By my hands!
オレに殺されてな。
i realise the screaming pain
hearing loud in my brain
but i'm going straight ahead with the scar
I should just get over it and I should just stop feeling it
wasurete shimaeba ii yo kanjinaku nacchaeba ii
and so I covered my grazed heart
surimuita kokoro ni futa wo shitan da
I don't care if I'm hurt 'cause I don't feel pain anymore
kizutsuitatte heki da yo mou itami wa nai kara ne
all while you limped on while dragging your feet behind you
sono ashi wo hikizuri nagara mo
I had lost sight of myself
miushinatta jibun jishin ga
which had crumbled loudly to the ground
oto wo taete kuzureteita
but then I realised it was just the sound of the wind...
kizukeba kaze no oto dake ga
I came here to tell you something following my deep scars
tsutae ni kita yo kizuato wo tadotte
before I am completely crushed by this vast world
sekai ni oshitsubusarete shimau mae ni
do you remember that sky of tears
oboeteru kana namida no sora wo
that pain protected you for me
ano itami ga kimi no koto wo mamotte kureta
that pain is always protecting you
sono itami ga itsumo kimi wo mamotterunda
can you hear me so am i
The End
さて… ご希望どおり 再現しよう。
Now... As you wished, I'll recreate...
アンタの死に様を！
your death!
《ゼツ : 天照と同じ
かわすことのできない術。
A jutsu which, like Amaterasu,
cannot be evaded?!
What kind of jutsu is it?!
いったい どんな術だってんだ？》
I get it!
(ゼツ)そうか さっきの火遁は
このためか。
That's what Sasuke's Fire Style Jutsu
was for earlier!
What do you mean?
どういうこと？
あの火遁攻撃の狙いは➡
The target of that Fire Style attack was
never Itachi to begin with!
はなから
イタチじゃなかったということだ。
だから どういうこと？
So what does that mean?
He purposely released
his Fire Style attack into the sky,
わざと火遁を空に打ち上げ➡
causing a sudden warmth
in the atmosphere
大気を急激にあたためて
上昇気流を発生させたのだ。
and he created an ascending air current!
上昇気流？
Ascending air current?
To form cumulonimbus...
In other words, thunder clouds!
積乱雲…
つまり雷雲を作るためだ。
だから それが どういう…。
So what does that mean?
Instead of using his own chakra...
己のチャクラエネルギーではなく
膨大な大気のエネルギーを利用して➡
he intends to take advantage of
the massive energy in the atmosphere
雷遁の術を行う気だ。
どんな？
to create a Lightning Style Jutsu!
What kind?
とにかく人間が チャクラから
性質変化で作るものとは➡
In any case, it'll be on
a totally different scale
than what anyone can create
using change in Chakra Nature alone.
規模が違うぞ。
そうか 天照の熱をも
利用するために➡
I see...
Sasuke purposely lured Itachi outside,
わざと外へ誘い出したのか。
so he could also use the heat
created by Amaterasu.
この術は 天から降る雷。
This jutsu brings down thunder
from the heavens.
オレは その力をアンタへと導くだけだ。
I merely direct its power toward you.
やはり そうか。
だとしたら避けられるわけがない。
Just as I thought...
Which is why it cannot be evaded.
どうして？
落雷は 1,000分の１秒。
Why not?!
A bolt of lightning is 1/1000th of a second.
音よりも速い。
It's faster than sound!
術の名は 麒麟。
The name of this jutsu is "Kirin".
何だ？
サスケは 雷をも手なずけたか。
What's that?!
Sasuke has tamed lightning?!
Come!
こい！
雷鳴とともに散れ！
Vanish with the roar of thunder...
うわっ！
クッ… これほどとは。
Such power...
イタチは 死んじゃったのか？
Did Itachi... die?
終わった… うっ…。
It's... over.
終わったぞ…。
It's over!
(イタチ)これが
お前の再現したかった死に様か？
Is this... the death you wanted to recreate?
クッ！
クソが！
Damn you!
That's...!
あれは…。
(イタチ)これがなければ
やられていたな。
Without this, I would have been dead.
なんだ？
What is that?!
本当に強くなったな サスケ…。
You really have... gotten stronger...
Sasuke.
今度は… オレの最後の切り札を
見せてやろう。
This time...
I shall show you my final trump card...
須佐能乎だ。
The Susano'o.
オレの最後の切り札を見せてやろう。
須佐能乎だ。
I shall show you my final trump card...
The Susano'o.
須佐能乎？
Susano'o?
月読と天照…
２つの能力を開眼したときに➡
Tsukuyomi and Amaterasu...
When these two powers awakened,
この眼に宿った
もうひとつの術だ。
one more jutsu took root in my eyes.
サスケ… お前の術は
これで 終わりか？
Sasuke, is that it for your jutsu?
隠している力があるなら
出し惜しみはしなくていいぞ。
If you are hiding another power,
don't hold back.
ここからが 本番だ。
The real battle is only beginning.
空が晴れていく…。
The sky is clearing...
さっきの術は どうやら
１発が 限界のようだな。 ん!?
It seems that last jutsu is limited
to one shot.
あれは!?
What's that?!
どうした？
チャクラが切れ 万策 尽きたか？
What's the matter?
Have you used up your chakra
and run out of options?
なに!? うっ！
What?!
(大蛇丸)あげるわ…。
I can give it to you...
私が 力を貸してあげるわ。
I can lend you power...
クソ！
Damn it!
(大蛇丸)私が必要なんでしょ？
サスケ君…。
You need me, don't you, Sasuke?
イタチに復讐するんじゃなかったの？
I thought you were going to
get revenge on Itachi?
さぁ 私の力を解き放ちなさい。
Now, release my power!
そうすれば あなたの願いは…。
Then your wish...
くっ！ うぅ…。
あぁ～!!
ぐぁ～っ!!
この感じ… 大蛇丸の八岐の術か。
Judging by the feel of it...
This is Orochimaru's
Eight-Headed Serpent Jutsu.
なんだ!? ありゃ！
What is that?!
サスケ自身のチャクラが
なくなったのにも関わらず➡
It's because Sasuke tried to
squeeze out more power
ムリに 力を出そうとしたからだ。
despite having no chakra!
取り込んで 抑えていた
大蛇丸のチャクラが 表へ…。
Orochimaru's chakra that he'd absorbed
and suppressed
has shoved its way to the surface!
出るものが出てきたな。
Finally, it comes out...
あれって…。
Is that...?!
(大蛇丸)フフフフフ…。
う… うぅ…。
相変わらず 口から
ゲロゲロとキモいヤツだな。
A gross fellow as always,
puking out stuff from his mouth.
文字どおり
ヘビのように しつこいヤツだ。
Persistent vermin like his namesake...
これよ… これを待っていたのよ。
This is it!
This is what I have been waiting for!
あなたのお陰で サスケ君の
抑えのチャクラが消えてくれたわ。
Thanks to you,
Sasuke's repressing chakra is gone!
これを機に
あの子の体をいただく。
Now's my chance to take over
the child's body!
そして…。
And...!
フフフフフフ…。
この程度の攻撃で
私が やられると思って？
You think I can be beaten
with that level of attack?
さて サスケ 次は どうする気だ？
Now then, Sasuke...
What will you do next?
この剣は まさか… 十拳剣!?
This sword! It can't be...!
The Totsuka Blade?!
イタチ… あなたが
隠し持って… ああっ…。
Itachi... You had it hidden
in your possession...?!
なんなの？ あの剣。
What is that sword anyway?
十拳剣。 別名
酒刈太刀と呼ばれる封印剣だ。
The Totsuka Blade,
also known as the Sakegari Blade,
is a sword of sealing.
突き刺した者を
酔夢の幻術世界に永久に飛ばし➡
It is said to trap and seal away
those it pierces
in a genjutsu world of drunken stupor
for all eternity.
封じ込めるといわれる。
剣そのものが封印術を帯びた
草薙剣のひと振りだ。
The blade itself is imbued with
a Sealing Jutsu
and is a variant of the Snake Sword.
ずっと大蛇丸が探していた。
Orochimaru has long searched for it.
やっぱ イタチは すげぇつえぇ…。
Itachi's power really is immense!
仕上げだ… サスケ。
This is it... Sasuke.
なんなんだ？ あのイタチの術。
What's with Itachi's jutsu?
ハア… ハア… ハア…。
うっ… ゴホッ ゴホッ…。
あの須佐能乎とかいう術
相当 リスクが大きいようだな。
That Susano'o jutsu...
it seems to be awfully risky.
でもさ サスケは
写輪眼ですらなくなってるし➡
But...
Sasuke's even lost his Sharingan
大蛇丸も
引き剥がされちゃったし➡
and he's been stripped of Orochimaru.
もう これは
イタチの勝ちじゃないの？
Don't you think Itachi's won
this one already?
これで… お前の眼は オレのものだ。
Now... your eyes are mine.
ゆっくり いただくとしよう。
I think I'll take my time to retrieve them.
うっ… ううっ…。
うわっ！ 何？
少し様子が変だな。
Wha--?! What's this?!
Something seems wrong...
ゴホッ… ゴホッ ゴホッ…。
クソッ… うお～っ！
Damn it!
あの須佐能乎とかいう術 あの盾で
すべての攻撃を弾き返してる。
That jutsu he called Susano'o...
Its shield is repelling every attack!
間違いない…
あれも霊器のひとつ。
There's no mistake about it...
That is also a spirit weapon.
すべてをはね返す
八咫鏡と呼ばれるものだ。
It's called the Yata Mirror and
is said to deflect all things.
それに 攻撃には十拳剣がある。
完全に無敵だ。
Combined with the Totsuka Blade
for attacks, he's invincible.
オレの眼だ… オレの…。
They're my eyes... Mine...
ちっ…。
うお～っ！
(ゼツ)イタチが倒れた。
Itachi went down?!
ウソ！ あれってイタチ死んでない？
No way?! Itachi is...
Itachi is dead?
サスケの勝ちだ。
It's Sasuke's victory.
どうにも腑に落ちないんだけど。
Something doesn't feel right...
何だ？
About what?
イタチの強さって
こんなもんじゃなかったでしょ。
Itachi's strength was greater than this.
His moves weren't normal...
本来の動きじゃなかったし。
様子が変だって
お前も言ってただろ。
Even you said something was weird.
確かに かわせるはずの攻撃を
かわせず 戦闘中に何度も吐血。
That's true...
He wasn't able to counter attacks
that he should have countered...
He coughed up blood several times
during the fight...
イタチはもとから
何らかの重大なダメージを➡
Maybe Itachi had sustained
serious damage even before the battle.
負っていたのかもしれない。
それって写輪眼の
使いすぎが原因？
Was it caused by excessive use
of his Sharingan?
いや それは断定できない。
No... There's no way we can tell.
もう少しで サスケの眼を取れたのに。
So close to getting Sasuke's eyes too.
you are next to me
omae ga tonari ni iru
you are laughing
omae ga waratte iru
you seem so happy
omae ga ureshisou de
so I laughed too
ore mo waratta
(マカロフ)皆の者 心して聞けい。
今から重大発表をする。
you were so innocent and naive
omae wa mujaki datta
天狼島から
ギルドに戻った その日より➡
you were so kindhearted
omae wa yasashi katta
女子のみ 制服を設定する！
ナース服かスク水限定じゃ！ ヤッホー！
you sometimes cried
omae wa tokidoki naki
(ルーシィ)何の話かしら!?
(エルザ)なるほど それは楽しみだな。
so I was troubled
ore wa komatta
のらない！ ここ怒るとこ！
(ミラジェーン)マスター ここは真面目に…。
who did I ask strength from at that time
dare yori tsuyosa wo motometa ano koro
すみましぇん！ ちょっとノリで…。
since that was my one and only weakness
ore no tatta hitotsu no yowasa ga
that was you
omae datta
and it was you
omae datta n da
I want to see you
aitai
overnights
yoru wo koete
over time
toki wo koete
I want to see you now
ima aitai
Next Episode
Damn it! What is this guy?!
All he's doing is trying to stall us!
Why can't I hit him with my Rasengan?!
No... That's not it!
I did hit him, yet...
Damn it!
We can't waste any more time!
I have to get past here...
I have to get to Sasuke!
Next time on Naruto Shippuden: "The Mystery of Tobi"
The Mystery of Tobi
Make sure to tune in next time!